PROFILE

After teaching preschool for four years, I began searching for an opportunity to learn something new. I love being creative, problem solving and being challenged in my work. Learning software development was my perfect solution. There is so much opportunity for growth, continuous learning, and creativity through design. I am excited to begin my professional career as a software developer.

PROJECTS

Make My Developpe - Front End Capstone

'Make My Developpe' is a single-page web application. It is a resource that dancers, training in ballet, can utilize to create training workouts and track their progress. This app was built using:

- React.js for framework
- HTML5 and CSS3 for styling
- Cloudinary for Image Management



KelleyCrittenden/Make-My-Developpe

Tails of Joy - Full Stack Capstone

'Tails of Joy' is a single-page web application . It allows users to view available dogs up for adoption and apply to adopt them. A user can then share their adoption story with others.

- Utilized ASP.NET, C#, React, JSX, CSS3 HTML5
- Designed Using Reacstrap
- Cloudinary for Image Management



KelleyCrittenden/Tails-of-Joy

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Nashville Software School
Full Stack Software Development, Certificate

St. Bonaventure University

Mass Communications, Media Studies

REACH ME AT:



585.610.3590



kelleylcrittenden@gmail.com



<u>linkedin.com/in/kelleycrittenden</u>



github.com/kelleycrittenden

KELLEY CRITTENDEN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School | May 2020 – November 2020

Intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. Offers individual and team-based projects and daily introduction of new material.

- Git and GitHub for version control
- Built Full Stack applications with ASP.NET and React
- Learned functional React with hooks
- Experience in remote collaboration using Agile Scum Development

Group Projects

Tabloid | ASP.NET, C#, HTML5, CSS3, React.js with Hooks, Reactstrap
Tabloid is a single page web app built by four classmates. It allows a user to add posts,
subscribe to other users, comment, get recommendations and more. Personally responsible
for the full CRUD functionality, allowing a user to create, edit and delete tags as well as
attach and remove tags on their post.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Preschool Teacher

First Baptist Church Of Dickson, INC. | Aug 2016 - May 2020

- Developed a careful and creative program suitable for preschool children
- Tracked children's progress
- Maintained ongoing open communication with parents and caregivers
- Responsible for individual classroom with 16 students
- Created daily lesson plans that included math, science, sensory and reading centers
- Designated and oversaw tasks assigned to teaching assistant

Assistant Preschool Teacher | Aug 2016 - May 2017

- Assisted in daily projects
- Prepared the classroom for lessons
- Cleared away materials and equipment after lessons
- Supported lead teacher in managing class behavior
- Assisted children who needed extra support to complete tasks

Bill of Materials / Inventory

Northern Lights Candles, Inc. | Oct 2003 – Jun 2007

- Updated bill of materials for products using SYSPRO
- Created and maintained all stock codes in Microsoft Excel
- Supervised product label production and inventory for orders

Product Label Design and Production | Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

- Designed product labels using Zebra Designer Pro
- Maintained label stock
- Prepared and printed all product labels for orders using a Zebra Printer

Quality Control Inspector | Jun 2002 - Aug 2002

- Inspected raw materials to ensure consistency and integrity
- Reported product problems or concerns to senior management
- Attempted repairs on broken or damaged products to determine the best way to scale those repairs

Laboratory Assistant

Allegany Eye Associates | Sep 1997 - June 2002

- Pulled and prepared all patient files for next day appointments
- Tinted lenses for custom patient orders
- Notified patients of order arrivals
- Organized all patient files in storage